[The Night Before the Staged Execution Rescue]
الليلة التي سبقت عملية الإنقاذ] [من ساحة الإعدام
♪ What's the cost of going against the wind? ♪
♪ إن سرتُ عكس الريح، فما الثمن؟ ♪
♪ Knowing you, knowing me, we live up to our promises ♪
♪ أعرفك وتعرفني، ولن نخلف وعدًا ♪
♪ Aligning the traces of our conviction ♪
♪ لتتطابق آثار قناعاتنا وتتوافق ♪
♪ As long as I'm with you ♪
♪ مهما طال هذا الطريق ♪
♪ The journey can stretch on forever ♪
♪ لا أرجو إلا أن أسير معك ♪
♪ Even if it puts my life on the line ♪
♪ ولو عبرنا الحياة والموت معًا ♪
Tomorrow's fake rescue from the execution ground
غدا سيتم اقتحام ساحة الإعدام بشكل زائف
♪ I shall never forget ♪
♪ لن أنسى ♪
is a life-or-death gamble.
إنها خطة ثمنها الحياة أو الموت
If this charade isn't convincing enough,
إذا لم تكن هذه الخطة واقعية
we won't gain the trust of Northern Qin.
فسيكون من الصعب كسب ثقة مملكة تشين الشمالية
You must strike me down without mercy,
يجب عليكم أن تهاجموني بقسوة
and I won't hold back either.
وأنا أيضا لن أتهاون معكم
I'll try my best to keep you all alive.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي للحفاظ على حياتكم جميعا
But swords and blades have no eyes—
لكن السيوف لا أعين لها
there's always a chance of an accident.
ومن الصعب ضمان عدم وقوع أي حوادث
-If anything were to... -Your Highness, no need to say more.
...إذا كان هناك - لا داعي لمزيد من الكلام يا ولي العهد -
Death is inevitable on the battlefield.
ففي ساحة المعركة، لا مفر من الموت
If this plan succeeds, it can at least
إذا نجحت هذه الخطة
secure more than a decade of peace and stability for the Northern Border.
فإنها ستضمن استقرار الحدود الشمالية لعشر سنوات على الأقل
We're willing to be the blade in Your Highness's hand!
نحن على استعداد أن نكون سيوفا في يدك يا ولي العهد
-We're willing! -To stand together through life and death!
مستعدون، نحن مستعدون سنعيش ونموت معا
Your Highness, you once said,
لقد قلت يا ولي العهد
"Who says we stand alone?
كيف يُقال لا ثوب لنا؟
We share weal and woe."
فنحن نتقاسم الرداء ذاته
Alright!
حسنا
How fitting—"Who says we stand alone? We share weal and woe."
يا له من قول رائع، "كيف يُقال لا ثوب لنا؟ "فنحن نتقاسم الرداء ذاته
Then let's face life and death together!
إذن فلنعش ونمت معا
[Key to the Phoenix Heart]
[مفتاح قلب العنقاء]
[Episode 26]
[الحلقة السادسة والعشرون]
[Huiyin Hall]
[قصر هويين]
Say something.
تحدث
Xie Jiayu! Our wedding's tomorrow.
شيه جيا يوي، حفل الزفاف غدا
You have to marry me
سواء أردت أم لا
whether you're willing to or not!
عليك أن تتزوجي مني
Keep breaking things like this,
إذا واصلت التحطيم هكذا
and there won't be many vases left in the palace.
فلن يتبق أي مزهريات في هذا القصر
How is it? Has His Majesty issued the decree?
ماذا؟ هل أصدر جلالته مرسوما؟
Xiao Wuyi's judgment was correct.
كان حُكم شياو وو يي صحيحا
After the An and Lu families were cleared of their charges,
بعد تبرئة عشيرتي آن ولو
the people's anger over the false charges fabricated by Northern Qin,
غضب الناس من القضايا الظالمة التي لفقتها تشين الشمالية
along with their hatred stemming from more than 2 decades of war,
والكراهية الناجمة عن أكثر من عشرين عاما من الحرب
have reached its peak.
وصلت إلى ذروتها
Public support for the Northern Expedition is now solid.
لقد اجتمع تأييد الشعب للحملة الشمالية
His Majesty has issued a decree approving the expedition
أصدر جلالته مرسوما بالموافقة على الحملة الشمالية
and ordered He Yuan to draft a proclamation for it.
وأمر خه يوان بكتابة إعلان الحملة الشمالية
As expected, nothing escapes his calculations.
كما هو متوقع، لا شيء يفلت من حساباته
Li Mao!
لي ماو
I'd rather die today than marry you!
حتى لو مت اليوم، فلن أتزوج منك
What's this?
ما هذا الشيء؟
Don't you want to root out
ألم تكن ترغب قبل الحملة الشمالية
all the Northern Qin spies in the palace before the Northern Expedition?
في القبض على جميع جواسيس تشين الشمالية في القصر؟
This item is called the caltrop fireball.
هذا الشيء يسمى الحسك الناري
It is recorded in the surviving fragments of "Essentials of Fire Attacks."
وهو مسجل في المخطوطة المتبقية "من "أساسيات الهجوم بالنار
Back then, Northern Qin was so desperate to kill Cui Jun
في ذلك الوقت، كانت تشين الشمالية في عجلة من أمرها لقتل تسوي جيون
precisely because they wanted to seize this item.
للاستيلاء على هذا الشيء
Before my master, Yuan Xiaoliu, passed away,
قبل وفاة معلمي يوان شياو ليو
he entrusted this blueprint to me.
أعطاني هذه المخطوطة
He said that the art of firearms
لقد قال إن فن الأسلحة النارية
was tied to the fate of the nation.
مرتبط بمصير البلاد
So if the Northern Qin spies learn of this item,
لذلك، إذا علم جواسيس تشين الشمالية بوجود هذا الشيء
even if it's a trap,
حتى لو كان هناك فخ
they'll surely risk their lives to obtain it.
فسيخاطرون بحياتهم من أجله بالتأكيد
That's wonderful news.
أليس هذا رائعا؟
With this item, the Northern Expedition is bound to succeed.
مع هذا الشيء ستنجح الحملة الشمالية بالتأكيد
But I've modified this blueprint. So don't let
لكنني عدلتُ هذه المخطوطة
the Directorate of Military Equipment blindly manufacture them.
لذا لا تدع رجال هيئة الأسلحة يصنعونها بشكل عشوائي
If they end up blowing themselves up instead,
إذا انفجرت وقتلت رجالنا
I won't take responsibility.
فلن أكون مسؤولة
Yaoyao.
جيا يوي
You still don't trust me.
ما زلت لا تثقين بي
I trust you,
أنا أثق بك
but I also have to guard against you.
لكنني يجب أن أحذر منك أيضا
Xiao Wuyi prides himself on his cleverness—
شياو وو يي يظن نفسه ذكيا
he factors in the people's will,
أخذ مشاعر الناس في الحسبان
and your ambitions as well.
وأخذ طموحك في الحسبان أيضا
He thinks he's thought of everything,
يظن أن خطته لا تشوبها شائبة
but in reality, he's just a fool
لكنه في الحقيقة مجرد أحمق
who doesn't value his own life.
لا يكترث بحياته
That's why I'm his last line of defense.
لذلك أنا ملاذه الأخير
I can't take that chance.
لا أجرؤ على المقامرة
Mao.
يا ماو
I won't harm you,
أنا لن أؤذيك
but I won't let you harm him either.
ولكنني لن أسمح لك بإيذائه أيضا
I just want both of you
كل ما أريده هو أن تكونا كلاكما
to stay alive and well.
بخير وعلى قيد الحياة
Alright.
حسنا
Then tomorrow's wedding
إذن حفل الزفاف غدا
will be the best opportunity to catch the spies.
هو أفضل فرصة للقبض على الجواسيس
Xie Jiayu, I'll give you one last chance!
شيه جيا يوي، سأمنحك فرصة أخرى
The wedding's tomorrow.
الزفاف غدا
Are you going to marry me or not?
هل ستتزوجينني أم لا؟
Will you give me the blueprints for the caltrop fireball or not?
هل ستعطينني مخططات الحسك الناري أم لا؟
If you're determined to die alongside Xiao Wuyi,
إذا كنت مصرّة على الموت مع شياو وو يي
I'll kill Xiao Ziqi right now.
فسأقتل شياو تسي تشي الآن
You wouldn't dare!
هل تجرؤ؟
Feng An!
يا فنغ آن
Yes, Your Highness.
خادمك رهن إشارتك
Take Xiao Ziqi to the Court of Judicial Review.
خذ شياو تسي تشي إلى محكمة دالي
Since his surname is Xiao,
بما أن لقبه شياو
let him be reunited with his family as soon as possible.
فلندعه يجتمع مع عائلته في أقرب وقت
Understood.
أمرك
Li Mao, you're out of your mind!
يا لي ماو، هل جننت؟
You won't even spare a child?
...ألن تستثني حتى طفلا وتدعه وشأنه
I've only kept him alive to make you obey,
لقد أبقيته على قيد الحياة فقط لأجعلك تطيعينني
but my patience is running out.
لكن صبري له حدود
The Grand Tutor is dead,
المعلم الأكبر قد مات
and the Xiao family has fallen.
وعائلة شياو قد هُزمت
Now, aside from my lingering affection for you,
الآن، باستثناء مشاعري القديمة تجاهك
you have nothing to rely on.
لم يعد لديك أي شيء تعتمدين عليه
Stop overestimating yourself.
لا تبالغي في تقدير نفسك
You're nothing more than my spoils of war.
أنت مجرد غنيمة من غنائمي
I'll give you the blueprints for the caltrop fireball.
سأعطيك مخططات الحسك الناري
But you must let Xiao Ziqi and He Yuanji go.
ولكن عليك أن تطلق سراح شياو تسي تشي وخه يوان جي
Fine.
حسنا
Let them go before the wedding!
أطلق سراحهما قبل الزفاف
Okay.
موافق
After all these years,
لقد مرت سنوات عديدة
you're still nothing like her.
لكنك ما زلت لا تشبهينها
Forgive me, Your Highness.
أرجوك سامحني يا صاحب السمو
Never mind.
انسي الأمر
Now that she's returned,
لقد عادت بالفعل
you don't have to keep up the act anymore.
لذا لا داعي لأن تستمري في التمثيل
Your Highness, please don't send me away.
يا صاحب السمو، لا تطردني
Please have pity on my devotion, Your Highness.
أتوسل إليك يا صاحب السمو أن تشفق على قلبي المخلص
I'm willing to serve Your Highness
أنا على استعداد لخدمة سموك
and Her Highness the Secondary Consort.
وخدمة المحظية
I've treated you so poorly,
أنا أعاملك بكل هذا السوء
yet why have you still not changed your feelings?
فلماذا لم يتغير حبك الأول؟
I've served Your Highness all these years
لقد اتبعتك يا صاحب السمو حتى الآن
and know full well the hardships Your Highness has faced.
وأعرف جيدا الصعوبات التي واجهتها
Even if I cannot be the one you love,
حتى لو لم أستطع أن أكون حبيبتك
I'm willing to be a bowl of tea or a lamp.
فأنا على استعداد لأن أكون مثل فنجان شاي أو مصباح لك
As long as I can bring you
طالما أنني أستطيع أن أجعل سموك تشعر
a moment of peace and comfort,
بلحظة من السلام والراحة
I'll feel content.
فسأكون راضية
Good.
حسنا
Then tomorrow, do something for me.
إذن غدا، ساعديني في أمر ما
Whatever Your Highness commands.
أنا تحت أمر سموك
Keep an eye on Xie Jiayu.
راقبي شيه جيا يوي جيدا
If she tries to pass anything to He Yuanji
إذا أرادت تسليم أي شيء إلى خه يوان جي
or Xiao Ziqi to take out of the palace,
أو شياو تسي تشي لإخراجه من القصر
swap it out for me.
استبدليه لي
That could be the key to victory in the Northern Expedition.
هذا هو مفتاح النصر في الحملة الشمالية
Understood.
أمرك
Also,
وأيضا
avoid Feng An.
تجنبي فنغ آن
He's a spy for Northern Qin.
إنه جاسوس من تشين الشمالية
What?
ماذا؟
Eunuch Feng is...
...الخادم فنغ، هو
Chan.
يا تشان
You're the only one I can trust.
أنت الوحيدة التي يمكنني الوثوق بها
I'll do my utmost to share Your Highness's burden.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي لأخفف عن سموك همومك
Your Highness, it's time to return to the palace.
أيتها المحظية، لنعد إلى القصر
Freeze!
توقف
Hold on.
انتظري لحظة
Miss Chan,
أرجو من السيدة تشان
I entrust Young Lady to your care from now on.
أن تعتني جيدا بالآنسة الشابة في المستقبل
Ziqi,
يا تسي تشي
hurry and thank Sister Chan.
لمَ لا تسرع وتقدم الشكر للأخت الكبرى تشان؟
No need for such formalities, Young Master.
لا داعي لهذه الرسميات أيها السيد الصغير
In the days to come,
أنا في المستقبل
I'll definitely take good care of your concubine mother.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي للاعتناء بخالتك
Let's go.
هيا بنا
Feng An has been discovered.
لقد انكشف أمر فنغ آن
The 3 people in his network are likely all exposed now.
أخشى أن الثلاثة الذين يعملون معه قد انكشفوا أيضا
Now,
الآن
you're the only ones who can get this blueprint out of the palace.
أنتن الوحيدات القادرات على إخراج هذه المخططات من القصر
Deliver this to His Highness immediately,
أرسلوها إلى سموه على الفور
and do not come back.
ولا تعدن أبدا
Understood.
أمرك
Freeze!
توقفن
When did you discover my identity?
متى اكتشفت أمري؟
I never did, actually.
لم أكتشفك
I tested everyone,
لقد اختبرتُ الجميع
and you were the only one who gave yourself away.
لكنك الوحيدة التي كشفت نفسها
The caltrop fireball is way too important.
الحسك الناري مهم للغاية
If Feng An were discovered,
إذا انكشف أمر فنغ آن
his accomplices would have no choice but to put their lives on the line.
فإن شركاءه سيضطرون للمخاطرة بحياتهم
Actually, ever since
في الحقيقة، منذ المرة الأولى التي
I first saw you by Mao's side,
رأيتك فيها بجانب ماو
something felt off to me.
شعرتُ بشيء غريب
The woman who once had the courage
تلك المرأة الشجاعة التي كانت على استعداد
to die alongside Prince Changsha...
للموت مع أمير تشانغشا
If you drink it, you'll die too.
إذا شربت هذا، ستموتين أنت أيضا
Then I'll go down with him.
إذن فلنهلك معا
How could she, after falling for someone,
كيف لها بعد أن وقعت في حب شخص ما
willingly copy another person and live as her replacement?
أن ترضى بتقليد أخرى وتكون بديلة لها؟
You were Eagle King's agent from the very beginning.
كنت من رجال الأمير النسر منذ البداية
I don't think so.
لا أعتقد ذلك
At first, she was probably just an inactive pawn—
في البداية، ربما كانت مجرد بيدق غير مهم
disguised as a dancer, gathering intelligence all over Jiankang.
تتظاهر بأنها راقصة لجمع المعلومات في جيانكانغ
When Prince Changsha rebelled,
عندما تمرد أمير تشانغشا
she realized something had changed.
أدركت أن الوضع قد تغير
To avoid being dragged into it,
ولكي لا تتورط
she fled the Lantai gathering.
هربت خلال ملتقى لانتاي
She never expected to run into you,
لكنها لم تتوقع أن تلتقي بك
and by a twist of fate, she ended up in Prince Jing'an's Household.
فدخلت قصر أمير جينغآن عن طريق الصدفة
So you never really
إذن منذ البداية
intended to save those dancers?
لم تكوني تنوين حقا إنقاذ هؤلاء الراقصات
You just wanted to create chaos
بل أردت إثارة الفوضى
so you could escape?
لتهربي بنفسك
Everyone has their own fate.
لكل شخص مصيره
As a spy, I can't afford to worry about such things.
الجواسيس في مهمتهم لا يمكنهم الاهتمام بكل شيء
You used Prince Jing'an's Household as a stepping stone
لقد اتخذت من قصر أمير جينغآن نقطة انطلاق
to get close to me,
للوصول إلى جانبي
taking it one step at a time
خطوة بخطوة، تتقدمين
to see how far you could go.
حيثما أمكنك الوصول
Precisely because you had no plan at all,
ولأنه لم تكن لديك خطة محددة
you left no traces behind.
لم تتركي أي أثر خلفك
You even
بل وحتى
deliberately arranged for Feng An to come to my side,
تعمدت ترتيب وجود فنغ آن هذا بجانبي
drawing my attention away.
لجذب انتباهي
But you still found out.
لكنك اكتشفتني رغم ذلك
Since you had already caught Feng An,
بما أنك قبضت على فنغ آن
why were you still not at assured?
لماذا ما زلت غير مطمئن؟
Things have always been like this
الملوك أشخاص وحيدون
for lonely rulers throughout history.
هكذا كان الحال على مر العصور
Do you have anything else to say?
هل لديك أي شيء آخر لتقوليه؟
Your Highness.
يا صاحب السمو
I have no complaints or regrets in this life.
أنا لا أحمل أي ندم أو ضغينة في هذه الحياة
I only wish Your Highness to take care
أتمنى فقط أن تعتني سموك بنفسك
and achieve your desires.
وأن تحقق كل ما تتمناه
By His Majesty's decree:
بأمر من جلالته
3 days from now, on the auspicious day, the imperial army—
بعد ثلاثة أيام، في يوم ميمون ستبدأ الحملة العسكرية
fully prepared and in high spirits—
الجيش الإمبراطوري منظم وجاهز
will set out on the Northern Expedition.
أقسم على إطلاق الحملة الشمالية
All Northern Qin spies within Jiankang City
جميع جواسيس تشين الشمالية في مدينة جيانكانغ
shall be sacrificed to the banner!
سيُقدَّمون جميعا قربانا لراية الحرب
Yes, Your Highness!
أمرك
The Northern Qin barbarians,
احتل أهل تشيوان رونغ من تشين الشمالية
with the nature of jackals and wolves, have usurped the Central Plains
بشراستهم التي تشبه الذئاب، السهول الوسطى
and torn our land apart for more than 20 years.
ومزقوا أرضنا لأكثر من عشرين عاما
They burned our ancestral temples,
لقد أحرقوا معابد أسلافنا
plundered our classics,
ونهبوا كتبنا
trampled the nine-tiered imperial palaces of the Capital,
وداسوا على قصور شانغجينغ الشاهقة
and defiled the clear skies and fertile lands in Heluo.
ودنسوا نقاء أراضينا الشاسعة
The gray-haired survivors still remember the blood spilled before Zhuque Street,
لا يزال الناجون الشيب يتذكرون الدماء التي سالت أمام شارع تشوتشيوه
and young children still hear the cries lingering on in the ancestral hall.
ولا يزال الأطفال الصغار يسمعون بكاء الأرواح في عوارض المعبد الإمبراطوري
Unless this grudge is avenged,
إن لم نثأر لهذا العداء
how can we stand before Heaven and Earth?
كيف لنا أن نقف في هذا العالم؟
Now our iron-clad armies have endured the autumn campaigns,
اليوم، دروعنا جاهزة بعد طول استعداد
our night watches have echoed without rest,
وأجراس الحراسة تدق طوال الليل
and the imperial forces have fully gathered their strength.
وجيشنا الإمبراطوري قد حشد قوة كافية
From the Observatory, we see the purple aura gathering in the east.
من منصة رصد النجوم نرى طاقة النصر تتجمع في الشرق
From the Yellow River, we hear the thunderous roar shaking the north.
ومن النهر الأصفر نسمع صوت الرعد يهز الشمال
How can we bear to watch the barbarian dust obscure the sun?
كيف نتحمل رؤية غبار البرابرة يحجب الشمس؟
How dare we forget the heart-wrenching anguish of our ancestors?
وهل نجرؤ على نسيان آلام آبائنا؟
Those who behead enemy soldiers shall be rewarded with 1000 taels of gold;
كل من يقطع رأس أسير يكافأ بألف قطعة من الذهب
those who seize banners or break through enemy lines shall be granted a fief of
ومن يستولي على راية ويخترق صفوف العدو يُمنح إقطاعية عشرة آلاف أسرة
10000 households. On the day this proclamation reaches you,
في يوم وصول هذا الأمر
we shall unfurl the dragon banners upon Mount Yin,
سنرفع رايات التنين في جبال ين
hang the heads of Qin spies at Hangu Pass,
ونعلق رؤوس قادة تشين عند ممر هانقو
restore the radiance of sun and moon over the ancient realm,
لنجعل الشمس والقمر يشرقان مجددا على عرشنا القديم
and rebuild our mountains and rivers upon the old borders.
ونعيد بناء وطننا في أراضينا السابقة
[Beifu]
[جيش الشمال]
The 3 armies jointly swear this blood oath:
جيوشنا الثلاثة تتشارك في هذا القسم بالدم
Until our realm is restored,
ما لم نستعد أرضنا
our blades shall not return to their sheaths.
لن نغمد سيوفنا
[Xiyue Restaurant]
[مطعم شي يوه]
Lan!
أخي
Chuan?
جينغ تشوان
Young Lord Xiao found you after all.
ولي العهد شياو قد وجدك بالفعل
[Jing Lan's brother Jing Chuan]
[شقيق جينغ لان الأصغر، جينغ تشوان]
Young Lord Xiao left this letter for you.
هذه رسالة من ولي العهد شياو
"I depart on a journey from which I may not return.
هذه رحلة بلا عودة
I hereby return Xiyue Restaurant to its rightful owner."
مطعم شي يوه أُعيد إلى صاحبه الأصلي
The Imperial Envoy came again?
لقد جاء المبعوث الإمبراطوري مجددا
Your Highness.
يا صاحب السمو
His Majesty has learned that the Southern Ye Army
سمع جلالته أن جيش يه الجنوبية قد عبر نهر جينغ
has crossed the Jing River and captured Luyang.
واخترق مدينة لويانغ
The court and the public are in an uproar.
مما أحدث صدمة في البلاط والبلاد
His Majesty has granted Your Highness the ceremonial tiger token
لقد منح سموك شارة النمر ومراسم السلطة
and ordered Your Highness to immediately dispatch troops to face the enemy.
وأمر سموك بإرسال القوات فورا لمواجهة العدو
My dear nephew finally couldn't hold back anymore.
ابن أخي هذا لم يعد يستطيع الجلوس ساكنا
For 3 years he wouldn't give me the tiger token,
لم يعطني شارة النمر لمدة ثلاث سنوات
but now that Luyang has fallen,
وبمجرد سقوط لويانغ
he's sent it over so quickly.
أرسلها بهذه السرعة
Chan had already delivered
شياو وو يي في السجن الإمبراطوري
the military strategy simulations
أما عن خطته الحربية التي أعطاها للي ماو
Xiao Wuyi did for Li Mao in prison to me.
فقد أرسلتها تشان منذ زمن
Prince Qi is far too impatient.
الأمير تشي هذا
He actually just copied their idea
متسرع جدا، ويقلد الآخرين بالفعل
and attacked
لقد هاجم بالفعل
our weakest western defense line
خطنا الغربي، وهو أضعف دفاعاتنا
without giving it any thought.
لا يفكر على الإطلاق
How could a leisurely prince who knows nothing but poetry and prose
أمير عاطل لا يجيد سوى كتابة الشعر
possibly understand military tactics?
كيف له أن يفهم في ترتيب القوات والتشكيلات؟
As long as the Beifu soldiers continue to attack the western front,
طالما استمرت قوات جيش الشمال في مهاجمة الخط الغربي
the cities behind it won't be easy to capture.
فلن يكون من السهل اختراق المدن التالية
Do not underestimate our enemy.
لا تستهن به
Understood.
أمرك
Your Highness.
سموك
Last night we caught a small-time bandit
الليلة الماضية، ألقينا القبض على لص
who actually tried to raid the camp and rescue Xiao Wuyi.
لقد حاول اقتحام المعسكر لإنقاذ شياو وو يي
Someone,
يا حراس
bring him up!
أحضروا الشخص
It's actually him.
إنه هو
He's still alive, huh?
إنه لا يزال على قيد الحياة
Alright then.
حسنا
Take him to the torture chamber
خذوه إلى غرفة التعذيب
and have him reunite with Xiao Wuyi's another guard.
لنجعل حارسي شياو وو يي يلتقيان
Aren't we sending him to Xiao Wuyi?
ألن نذهب للبحث عن شياو وو يي؟
These days,
خلال هذه الأيام
we've tried both carrots and sticks on him,
استخدمنا معه كل الأساليب اللينة منها والقاسية
but he just wouldn't budge.
لكنه لم يتفوه بكلمة
He even managed to escape 3 times.
وحاول الهروب ثلاث مرات
If he were to give in that easily,
لو أنه استسلم بهذه السهولة
I'd find it suspicious. Take him away.
لشعرتُ أنه هناك خطب ما، خذوه
Will you talk or not?
هل ستتكلمي أم لا؟
His Highness the Eagle King has arrived!
وصول سمو الأمير النسر
What a loyal young lady.
!يا لها من فتاة صغيرة مخلصة
We caught an old friend of yours last night.
الليلة الماضية، لقد ألقينا القبض على أحد معارفكم القدامى
Qing Long?
تشينغ لونغ
He followed us all the way here.
لقد لحق بنا إلى هنا
He had been hiding outside the camp for the past few days,
كان يختبئ خارج المعسكر في الأيام القليلة الماضية
trying everything to save Xiao Wuyi, but failed.
وحاول إنقاذ شياو وو يي بشتى الطرق ولكنه فشل
And he was caught last night.
أمس وقع في الفخ
Since you survived, you should try to remain that way!
ما دمتَ على قيد الحياة، فعليك أن تعيش جيدا
Why come here to die?
لماذا أتيت تبحث عن الموت؟
There are no deserters in the Beifu Army.
لا يوجد هاربون من جيش الشمال
With you and His Highness here,
أنت وولي العهد هنا
if I hadn't come to save you and had chosen to flee for my own life,
إن لم آت لإنقاذكما وأهرب لأنجو بحياتي
what kind of friend would that make me?
فأي نوع من الإخوة أكون؟
If you're scared,
إن كنت خائفا
just hand over the chance to go to Northern Qin with His Highness.
فدعني أذهب مع ولي العهد مباشرة إلى تشين الشمالية وهذا يكفي
Quiet.
لا تثيري المشاكل
Me, scared?
ممَ الخوف؟
I'm just worried that if I don't win the draw,
أنا أخشى ألا يتم اختياري
you'll steal my chance
وتخطفي مني فرصة التألق
to prove myself again.
مجددا
A bet is a bet.
الخاسر في الرهان عليه الإقرار بالهزيمة
I won.
إن فزتُ أنا
His Highness and I will go to Northern Qin as bait,
فسأذهب أنا وولي العهد إلى تشين الشمالية لنكون الطُعم
and you'll lay in ambush outside.
وأنت ستكون الكمين في الخارج
Honestly, there was never any need for a draw.
في الحقيقة، لا حاجة للاختيار
With a brain like yours,
بعقلك هذا
how could you possibly outmaneuver the Eagle King?
كيف ستتعامل مع الأمير النسر؟
How many times do you plan to pull that trick on him?
كم مرة أخرى تريدين أن تخدعيه بهذه الحيلة؟
I hope this isn't the last time.
آمل ألا تكون هذه هي المرة الأخيرة
Go get some rest.
اذهبي واستريحي
We're hitting the road first thing tomorrow morning.
سننطلق في صباح الغد
Rest assured, Your Highness.
اطمئن يا ولي العهد
I'll try to stage a few more rescue attempts before I get captured.
سأحاول إنقاذك عدة مرات حتى يتم إلقاء القبض عليّ
That way, it will seem more convincing.
بهذه الطريقة، سأبدو أكثر مصداقية
Don't lose your life doing this.
لا تفقد حياتك
Even if I do, it doesn't matter.
لا بأس إن فقدتها
A suicide mission
إنها خطة التضحية بالنفس
can't work without someone dying.
كيف لا يموت فيها أحد؟
Is that why you refused to tell Yan Yue?
هذا هو السبب في أنك لا تريد إخبار يان يوه
She's soft-hearted.
إنها طيبة القلب
And she'd definitely choose to be the one waiting outside.
كما أنها بالتأكيد ستختار دور من يكون في الخارج
A prison break is like a gamble—
الهروب من السجن أمر خطير
the slightest mistake means death.
أي خطأ بسيط قد يكلف الشخص حياته
I'll do it.
من الأفضل أن أقوم أنا بذلك
You two share such a deep bond of affection and loyalty,
العلاقة بينكما عميقة ومليئة بالمشاعر
which makes you ideal subjects for interrogation.
وهذا يجعلكما الأنسب للتعذيب
I've witnessed Miss Yan Yue's loyalty with my own eyes.
لقد شهدتُ على ولاء الآنسة يان يوه
But since ancient times, it's been hard to balance loyalty and righteousness.
ولكن منذ القدم، من الصعب الموازنة بين الولاء والوفاء
Young man.
يا فتى
Do you want to know
ألا تريد أن تعرف
if she has feelings for you?
ما إذا كانت معجبة بك أم لا؟
I can help you.
يمكنني مساعدتك
Qing Long!
تشينغ لونغ
Torture them one after another.
تناوبوا عليه
Since this lady refuses to talk,
هذه الفتاة ترفض الكلام
keep interrogating him.
فاستمروا في استجوابه
One of them is bound to give in.
لا بد أن أحدهما سيتكلم
Yes, Your Highness.
أمرك
Take a look, Young Lord Xiao,
يا ولي العهد، ألق نظرة
These two were so affectionate and loyal to each other,
هذان الاثنان حبهما عميق جدا
yet they only held out for 4 hours
بعد أربع ساعات فقط من التعذيب
before drawing this defense map of the Northern Border.
رسَما خريطة الدفاع عن الحدود الشمالية هذه
You're truly a man
أنت حقا
without a shred of compassion.
تفتقر تماما إلى حس الرحمة
You're nothing but a stray dog,
مجرد كلب ضال
yet they've followed you through thick and thin.
وهما يتبعانك بإخلاص ودون تخلٍ
Aren't you moved at all?
هل يُعقل أنك لا تتأثر بذلك ولو قليلا؟
Aren't their lives worth more than Li Mao's?
حياتهما ليست أغلى من حياة لي ماو
The soldiers of our Beifu Army have always risked their lives
جنود جيش الشمال يضحون بحياتهم
to protect the common people.
من أجل حماية الشعب
You want me to betray Ye
هل تريدني من أجل حياتهما
and abandon the people of the Northern Border
أن أخون مملكة يه الكبرى
just to save their lives?
وأتخلى عن شعب الحدود الشمالية؟
Mulian Yu,
مو ليان يوي
when did you become so foolish?
متى أصبحت غبيا هكذا؟
Now that you've mentioned the common people,
بما أنك يا ولي العهد قد ذكرت الشعب
this is perfect. Guards,
حسنا، يا رجال
bring the common people over!
أحضروا الشعب إلى هنا
Move!
تحركوا
Faster! Faster!
أسرعوا، أسرعوا
Move! Faster!
تحركوا، أسرعوا
Move!
تحرك
Move! Get in!
تحرك، ادخل
Hurry up!
أسرع
Move faster!
تحركوا بسرعة، أسرعوا
Move! Faster!
تحركوا بسرعة
The weather's perfect today—
الطقس اليوم مثالي
an excellent chance for a 100-pace archery contest.
إنها فرصة جيدة لإظهار مهارة الرماية
Back in Jiankang,
في الماضي في جيانكانغ
I lost to you.
خسرتُ أمامك
Let's have another match today.
لنتنافس مرة أخرى اليوم
If I lose again,
إذا خسرتُ مرة أخرى
I'll set Qing Long and Yan Yue free.
سأطلق سراح تشينغ لونغ ويان يوه
Do you guys know who he is?
هل تعرفون من هو؟
He's none other than Crown Prince Wenxi,
إنه الشخص الذي انتظرتموه طوال حياتكم
the one you've spent your entire lives waiting for!
ولي عهد ونشي
Save us, Your Highness!
أنقذنا يا ولي العهد
Please save us!
!النجدة
Over these years, the rumor "when the Phoenix Heart Tokens appear,
خلال هذه السنوات، ليس فقط في يه الجنوبية
peace shall be restored in the world" has spread far and wide—
بل حتى في شانغجينغ تنتشر شائعة
not only across Southern Ye, but even in the Capital.
أن ظهور تشيوه قو سيجلب السلام للعالم
Who among these refugees from Southern Ye
هؤلاء الناجون من مملكة يه الجنوبية
does not long for you, Crown Prince Wenxi, to reappear in this world
من منهم لا يتوق إلى عودة ولي عهد ونشي إلى العالم
and rescue them from their dire straits?
لينقذهم من محنتهم؟
Now that you've come here,
والآن بما أنك أتيت
I'm curious to see
أريد أن أرى بنفسي
if you can really turn a blind eye to them.
هل يمكنك تجاهلهم حقا أم لا؟
Shoot!
هيا
Stop!
توقف
The defense map drawn by Xiao Wuyi
خريطة الدفاع التي رسمها شياو وو يي
is different from the one drawn by Qing Long and Yan Yue.
تختلف عن خريطة تشينغ لونغ ويان يوه
Which one is right?
أيهما هي الحقيقية؟
We'll know once we put it to the test.
لما لا نجرب لنعرف ذلك؟
From 3 to 5 a.m. this morning,
الليلة الماضية في الثالثة فجرا
Eagle King dispatched 3 scouting units
أرسل الأمير النسر كتيبة الاستطلاع
to launch feigned attacks on Qingxi,
لشن هجوم وهمي على تشينغشي
Yingchuan, and Sansha.
وينغتشوان، وسانشا
What about Wuyi?
ماذا عن وو يي؟
Is there any news about him?
هل هناك أي أخبار عنه؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد
But the fact that Eagle King feigned attacks on those 3 locations
لكن قدرة الأمير النسر على شن هجوم وهمي على هذه الأماكن الثلاثة
shows that he's starting to trust Wuyi.
توضح أنه بدأ يثق في وو يي
Wuyi's plan is halfway to success.
خطة وو يي نجحت نصفها بالفعل
Eagle King is cunning.
الأمير النسر ماكر
We can't fully trust him.
لا يمكننا أن نثق به تماما
I must make sure he comes back alive.
يجب أن أعيده حيا
By the way,
بالمناسبة
an old acquaintance returned last night.
عاد صديق قديم الليلة الماضية
He said he had something very important to give you,
وقال إن لديه شيئا مهما جدا ليسلمه لك
and that it could only be given to you.
ويجب أن يسلمه لك أنت فقط
Who is it?
مَن؟
Be careful.
أنزلوه ببطء
Cui Shao'an?
تسوي شاو آن
How have you been?
كيف حالك؟
Thankfully, I've fulfilled the task you entrusted to me.
لحسن الحظ، لم أخيب ظنك
I found it.
لقد وجدته
Just as you said in the letter,
تماما كما ذكرت في رسالتك
it's not ore,
إنه ليس خاما
but a slurry-like substance.
بل مادة تشبه المعجون
Get the caltrop fireball ready.
جهز الحسك الناري
We'll test it right now.
سنجرب الآن
You must be extra careful.
عليك أن تكوني حذرة
The power of this thing goes far beyond your imagination.
قوة هذا الشيء تفوق خيالك بكثير
No matter how dangerous it is, we must try it.
مهما كان خطيرا، يجب أن أجربه
Ancient texts record that the caltrop fireball
وفقا لما هو مسجل في الكتب القديمة عن الحسك الناري
burns with the force of a collapsing mountain,
نيرانه كالجبال المنهارة
its flames twisting like lightning,
وألسنة لهبه كالبرق الدوار
capable of determining victory across vast fields.
يحسم النصر في ساحات المعارك الشاسعة
To win this battle,
من أجل الفوز في هذه المعركة
and to ensure Wuyi returns safely,
ومن أجل عودة وو يي سالما
no matter how dangerous it is, we must give it a try.
مهما كانت المخاطر، يجب أن نحاول
The three groups of scouts I dispatched,
الفرق الاستطلاعية الثلاث التي أرسلتها
following the map you drew,
باتباع الخريطة التي رسمتها يا ولي العهد
were indeed completely wiped out.
قد أُبيدت بالكامل كما هو متوقع
It seems this map is correct.
يبدو أن هذه الخريطة حقيقية
Have Qing Long and Yan Yue been released?
هل أطلقت سراح تشينغ لونغ ويان يوه؟
I always keep my word—
أنا دائما أفي بوعدي
as long as you cooperate with me.
طالما أنك تتعاون معي
There are 2 subtle errors on this map
هناك خطآن مخفيان في هذه الخريطة
that I left on purpose.
وقد تركتهما عن قصد
If Your Highness wants to cooperate with me,
يا صاحب السمو، إذا كنت ترغب في التعاون
you must first agree to one more condition.
فعليك تلبية شرط آخر لي
That's good.
هذا أفضل بكثير
That's more like the Xiao Wuyi I know.
هذا هو شياو وو يي الذي أعرفه
Go ahead. What condition is it?
تكلم، ما هو شرطك؟
I want the Capital.
أريد الذهاب إلى شانغجينغ
I'm Crown Prince Wenxi.
أنا ولي عهد ونشي
I'm determined to lead the people of Ye back to our former capital.
ويجب أن أقود شعب يه الكبرى للعودة إلى عاصمتنا القديمة
Xiao Wuyi, oh, Xiao Wuyi.
شياو وو يي، يا شياو وو يي
Your demand is a little too ambitious, isn't it?
شهيتك هذه كبيرة جدا
At this point,
في هذه المرحلة
is Your Highness really in any position to bargain?
هل ما زلت في وضع يسمح لك بالمساومة يا صاحب السمو؟
The young emperor of Northern Qin is wary of you—
إمبراطور تشين الشمالية الشاب يخشاك
he's cut off your supplies, sent a military inspector,
قطع عنك الإمدادات وأرسل مشرفا عسكريا
and now seeks to use Li Mao's forces
والآن يريد استغلال لي ماو
to wipe out your remaining 30,000 Black Eagle Army soldiers.
لإبادة جيش النسر الأسود خاصتك البالغ ثلاثين ألفا بالكامل
Now that a blade's already pressed against Your Highness's neck,
الآن، السيف مسلط على رقبتك يا صاحب السمو
do you really have a choice?
فهل لدى سموك خيار آخر؟
I don't want a single soldier from Your Highness.
لن آخذ من سموك جنديا واحدا
I only want the survivors of our Ye.
كل ما أريده هم رعايا يه الكبرى المتبقين
If I was able to build one Beifu Army,
تمكنتُ من تدريب جنود جيش الشمال
then I can build a second one.
وسأتمكن من تدريب جيش ثانٍ بالتأكيد
When the time comes, you and I will join forces to defeat Li Mao's army.
حينها، سنتحد لهزيمة جيش لي ماو
You can then march south
ويمكنك التوجه جنوبا
and capture Jiankang,
واحتلال جيانكانغ
and then advance westward.
ثم تتقدم بجيشك غربا
What, did I hit the nail on the head?
ماذا؟ هل أُصبت كبد الحقيقة؟
Isn't the land of Xizhou
أكثر ما تريده يا صاحب السمو
what Your Highness desires most?
أليست هي أراضي الولاية الغربية؟
Your Highness!
يا صاحب السمو
Are you really going to hand the Capital over to Xiao Wuyi?
يا صاحب السمو، هل ستسلم شانغجينغ حقا إلى شياو وو يي؟
That's treason.
هذه خيانة للوطن
So that was a lie, Your Highness?
يا صاحب السمو، أنت تخدعه
Once you get
طالما أننا نحصل منه
the complete Northern Border defense map from him
على خريطة الدفاع الكاملة للحدود الشمالية
and crush Li Mao's army,
ونهزم جيش لي ماو
then
حينها
we can get rid of Xiao Wuyi.
يمكننا التخلص من شياو وو يي
But that Xiao Wuyi
لكن شياو وو يي هذا
is far too clever.
ذكي جدا
He saw right through the fact
لقد رأى من خلال خطتي على الفور
that what I desire most is Xizhou.
أن ما أريده حقا هي الولاية الغربية
Could it be that he has set some kind of trap
هل يمكن أنه نصب لي فخا
and is waiting for me to fall into it?
وينتظرني لأقع فيه؟
If Your Highness remains concerned about Xiao Wuyi,
يا صاحب السمو إذا كنت قلقا دائما بشأن شياو وو يي
why not force him into a corner where he has no way out?
فمن الأفضل أن تدفعه إلى طريق مسدود
Your Highness, are you still unwell today?
يا صاحب السمو، ما زلت مريضا اليوم
I've recovered. I shall receive the decree.
لقد تعافيت، وأنا أتلقى الأمر
Southern Ye harbors the ambitions of a wild beast,
يه الجنوبية لديها طموح الذئب
coveting our territory.
يطمعون في أراضي مملكتنا
They're truly a great threat to our nation.
إنهم حقا خطر كبير على البلاد
Upon hearing the news,
عندما سمعتُ الخبر
I wished I could immediately don my armor and take the battlefield myself,
تمنيت لو أستطيع ارتداء درعي على الفور
fighting the enemy to the death.
لخوض معركة حياة أو موت مع العدو
I hereby order you to lead the counterattack,
لذا، آمرك يا عمي بمواجهة العدو
hold the line at Luyang,
وصده في لويانغ بقوة
reclaim our lost lands,
واستعادة الأراضي المفقودة
and avenge this national humiliation.
لغسل عار الأمة
As for Xiao Wuyi, use him if he proves capable.
استخدم شياو وو يي إن كان مفيدا
If not, execute him.
إن لم تتمكن من استخدامه، يمكنك قتله
If you fear that Xiao Wuyi might carry out a suicide mission,
إن كنت قلقا من أن شياو وو يي قد يلجأ إلى حيلة التضحية بالنفس
I have a way to help you test Xiao Wuyi's true intentions.
فلدي طريقة لاختبار ولائه نيابة عنك
Eat up.
كُلي
Your brother has arrived outside Luyang City.
أخوك قد وصل إلى خارج مدينة لويانغ بالفعل
He can bring you home now.
يمكنه أن يعيدك
This is the sound of our Beifu Army's war drums as they charge.
هذا صوت طبول الحرب لجيش الشمال المهاجم
Our young emperor's army has already crossed the Qin Mountains.
جيش إمبراطوري الشاب قد عبر جبال تشين
Right now, with the Beifu Army ahead of me
في هذه اللحظة، جيش الشمال أمامي
and our young emperor's army behind me,
وجيش إمبراطوري الشاب خلفي
two sharp blades are pressed against my head.
كلتا الشفرتين الحادتين موجهتان نحوي
Young Lord Xiao, you're the only one who can save me now.
الوحيد الذي يستطيع إنقاذي هو أنت يا ولي العهد شياو
Young Lord Xiao.
يا ولي العهد
Can you show me
هل يمكنك أن تمنحني
and the world
وتمنح العالم
this reason?
فرصة لرؤية هذا السبب؟
What do you want me to do?
ما الذي تريدني أن أفعله؟
I remember a few years ago,
أتذكر، قبل بضع سنوات
at Lingfeng Fort in Guazhou,
في حصن لينغفنغ بقواتشو
Li Lejun murdered Princess Yunzhao
لي له جيون قتلت أميرة يونتشاو
and returned to Jiankang.
وعادت إلى جيانكانغ
You and Xie Jiayu teamed up to uncover the real culprit.
أنت وشيه جيا يوي تعاونتما لكشف القاتل الحقيقي
You originally wanted to kill that murderer,
كنتما تنويان في الأصل الانتقام بقتل عدوتكما
but Li Lejun clung to life
لكن لي له جيون تشبثت بالحياة
and voluntarily defected to me.
ولجأت إليّ من تلقاء نفسها
Back then, Xie Jiayu once said:
في ذلك الوقت، قالت شيه جيا يوي جملة لها
"If one day
يوما ما
I see Li Lejun again..."
إذا رأيتك يا لي له جيون مرة أخرى
"I'll surely take your life."
سوف أقتلك بالتأكيد
Your Northern Qin spies truly live up to their reputation.
جواسيس تشين الشمالية يستحقون سمعتهم حقا
They even overheard every word of
حتى محادثتي الخاصة مع لي ماو
my private conversation with Li Mao.
استطاعوا سماعها بوضوح تام
Then may I ask, Young Lord Xiao,
اسمح لي أن أسألك يا ولي العهد
does that statement still stand?
هل ما زالت هذه الكلمات سارية المفعول؟
Young Lord Xiao.
يا ولي العهد
Today, I will
اليوم، أنا
give you a chance to fulfill your promise.
سأمنحك فرصة للوفاء بوعدك
The Northern Qin barbarians,
أهل تشيوان رونغ من تشين الشمالية
with the nature of jackals and wolves,
بطباعهم الشبيهة بالذئاب
have usurped the Central Plains
احتلوا السهول الوسطى
and torn our land apart for more than 20 years.
ومزقوا أراضينا لأكثر من عشرين عاما
They trampled the nine-tiered imperial palaces of the Capital,
وداسوا على قصور شانغجينغ الشاهقة
and defiled the clear skies and fertile lands in Heluo.
ودنسوا نقاء أراضينا الشاسعة
Now our iron-clad armies have endured the autumn campaigns,
والآن، بعد طول استعداد
our night watches have echoed without rest,
أجراس الحراسة تدق طوال الليل
and the imperial forces have fully gathered their strength.
وجيشنا الإمبراطوري قد حشد قواته
Those who seize banners or break through enemy lines shall be granted 10000 households!
من يستولي على الراية ويقتحم صفوف العدو سيُمنح إقطاعية عشرة آلاف أسرة
Your Highness, they're not responding. What should we do?
يا صاحب السمو، ماذا لو لم يكن هناك رد؟
Keep challenging them.
استمروا في تحديهم للنزال
Your Highness, someone has come out over there.
يا صاحب السمو، لقد خرج شخص من هناك
Lejun!
له جيون
Your brother is right across from us.
أخوك في الجهة المقابلة تماما
He's here to pick you up.
لقد أتى ليأخذك
Go on.
اذهبي
Mulian Yu.
مو ليان يوي
I don't regret coming to Northern Qin,
أنا لا أندم على مجيئي إلى تشين الشمالية
nor do I regret marrying you.
ولا أندم على زواجي منك
From the moment I stepped onto the land of Northern Qin,
منذ اللحظة التي وطأت فيها قدمي أرض تشين الشمالية
I knew it would end like this.
كنتُ أعلم أن هذه ستكون النهاية
But in the next life,
فقط في الحياة القادمة
let's not cross paths again.
دعنا لا نلتقي مرة أخرى
Prince Qi!
أيها الأمير تشي
See clearly who I am!
انظر بوضوح من تكون؟
Let my sister go!
أطلق سراح أختي
If you're willing to trade Luyang City for your sister's life,
إذا كنت على استعداد لمقايضة مدينة لويانغ بحياة أختك
I'll release her immediately!
فسأطلق سراحها على الفور
Young Lord Xiao.
يا ولي العهد
The grudge of ruining your reputation and taking your power,
حان الوقت للثأر من تشويه السمعة
and the hatred of wiping out your clan and taking your wife—
واغتصاب السلطة وإبادة العائلة
the time has come to settle these debts.
وسرقة الزوجة
Xiao Wuyi.
شياو وو يي
You traitor!
أيها الخائن
Kill me if you want.
إن أردت قتلي فاقتلني
I, Li Lejun, will never back down!
أنا لي له جيون، لن أستسلم أبدا
Wuyi!
يا وو يي
No!
لا تفعل
Wait.
انتظر
Give Li Mao the chance to fire 3 arrows.
أعط لي ماو فرصة بثلاثة سهام
I'd like to see
أريد أن أرى
if he's willing to sacrifice his sister's life.
هل هو على استعداد للتضحية بحياة أخته أم لا؟
Soldiers of Beifu!
يا جنود جيش الشمال
Xiao Wuyi has committed treason
شياو وو يي قد خان البلاد
and surrendered to Northern Qin!
واستسلم لتشين الشمالية
He's no longer your commander!
هو لم يعد قائدكم
He's a traitor!
إنه خائن
Li Lejun?
لي له جيون
Young Lord Xiao, I hope you've been well.
ولي العهد شياو، لم نلتق منذ زمن
Weren't you put under house arrest by the Eagle King?
ألم يضعك الأمير النسر تحت الإقامة الجبرية؟
I've already taken a deadly poison.
لقد تناولتُ سُما قاتلا بالفعل
My time is almost up.
وموتي وشيك
What's the point of keeping me locked up?
فما فائدة حبسي بعد الآن؟
What?
ماذا؟
Xiao Wuyi.
شياو وو يي
I came to ask you for a favor.
لقد أتيت لأطلب منك معروفا
Tomorrow, when the 2 armies face off on the battlefield,
غدا، في ساحة المعركة بين الجيشين
could you please
هل يمكنك
not let me die at the hands of the Northern Qin soldiers?
ألا تدعني أموت على أيدي جنود تشين الشمالية؟
I hope
أتمنى
you can kill me yourself.
أن تقتلني بيديك
Reason?
وما السبب؟
I owe Jiayu a life anyway.
أنا أدين بحياتي لجيا يوي في الأصل
If you take my life,
فلتأخذها أنت
I can accept it.
أنا أقبل بذلك
Your Highness! Your Highness, no!
يا صاحب السمو، لا تفعل
Could it be that
هل يمكن
Eagle King is just testing Wuyi with all this?
أن كل هذا كان اختبارا من الأمير النسر لوو يي؟
If Wuyi doesn't shoot Li Lejun in front of the 2 armies,
إن لم يقتل وو يي لي له جيون أمام الجيشين
he'll be completely exposed,
فسيُكشف أمره بالكامل
and the entire plan will fall apart at the last moment.
وستفشل كل الخطط
Soldiers of Ye!
يا جنود يه الكبرى
My brother has told me since I was young
أخبرني أخي منذ صغري
that the elite troops of Ye
أن جنود يه الكبرى النخبة
must fight for the land and people of Ye!
يجب أن يقاتلوا من أجل أرض وشعب يه الكبرى
I've already taken poison.
لقد تناولتُ السُم بالفعل
Death is only a matter of time for me.
وسأموت عاجلا أم آجلا
But I'm Princess Pingning of Ye.
لكنني أميرة بينغنينغ من يه الكبرى
My father, mother, my brothers and sisters—
أبي الأمير، وأمي، وإخوتي وأخواتي
so many of them were killed by the people of Northern Qin.
قُتلوا جميعا على يد جنود تشين الشمالية
No matter what,
أنا لي له جيون
I, Li Lejun,
ومهما حدث
cannot die at their hands.
لا يمكنني أن أموت على يد جنود تشين الشمالية
This
هذا
isn't the whole truth, is it?
ليس كل ما في قلبك من حقيقة، أليس كذلك؟
You're right.
نعم
There's a third reason.
هناك سبب ثالث
Lejun!
له جيون
Today,
حياتي اليوم
as I give my life for Ye,
أضحي بها من أجل يه الكبرى
I die a worthy death.
وهذا الموت في محله
Soldiers of the Beifu Army!
يا جنود جيش الشمال
Li Mao killed my parents
لي ماو قتل والدي
and took my wife.
واستولى على زوجتي
My hatred for him is boundless!
هذه كراهية لا تُغتفر
The Eagle King has promised me the Capital.
لقد وعدني الأمير النسر بالذهاب إلى شانغجينغ
If you surrender now,
إن استسلمتم
once we reclaim our homeland,
وعندما نعود في المستقبل
you'll be granted rank and honors.
سأمنحكم ترقيات ومناصب
As for those who refuse to surrender,
أما من يرفض الاستسلام
when we meet again on the battlefield,
فإذا التقينا في ساحة المعركة مجددا
expect no mercy.
فلا تترددوا في قتلي
Your Highness Prince Qi!
يا صاحب السمو الأمير تشي
Your sister has sacrificed for you her whole life!
أختك ضحت بحياتها من أجلك
Yet you aren't willing to trade a city
ألا ترغب حتى في التضحية بمدينة واحدة
for her life?
مقابل حياتها؟
Your Highness has been hiding
لقد كنتَ تخفي طوال هذه السنوات
the Regent of Southern Ye's sister all these years.
أخت الوصي على عرش يه الجنوبية
How do you want to show His Majesty your loyalty?
فكيف لجلالة الإمبراطور أن يثق بولائك؟
Young Lord Xiao.
يا ولي العهد
Xiao Wuyi!
شياو وو يي
Your Highness!
يا صاحب السمو
If my brother is to become a true emperor,
إذا أراد أخي أن يصبح إمبراطورا حقيقيا
he must free himself from your influence—
فعليه أن يتخلص من سيطرتك
not only from your command over the Beifu Army,
ليس فقط السلطة العسكرية لجيش الشمال
but also from the hold you have over his heart.
بل أيضا القلب والمشاعر
I once thought
كنتُ أظن
you merely viewed my brother
أنك تتعامل مع أخي
as a stepping stone to seize power.
كمجرد أداة للاستيلاء على السلطة
But now it seems
لكن يبدو الآن
you're even more ruthless toward yourself than toward others,
أنك أقسى على نفسك من الآخرين
and you care even less about your status as Crown Prince Wenxi.
بل ولا تهتم بهوية ولي عهد ونشي بشكل أكبر
A person like you has no weaknesses.
شخص مثلك ليس له نقاط ضعف
The line between god and demon lies in a single thought.
يمكنك أن تكون طيبا أو خيّرا في لمح البصر
Yet if one day
ولكن إذا جاء يوم
your paths diverge,
ووصلتما إلى مفترق طرق
what will become of my brother?
فماذا سيفعل أخي؟
If you truly have faith in him,
إن كنتَ تثق به حقا
then please allow him
فاسمح له
to stand before you as a true rival.
بأن يصبح خصمك الحقيقي